guys I think this is a pretty cool one
even though this is in terms of X you
can still find the exact value of this
red region if you want to try this on
your own posit because I'm going to
solve it in three two one first let's
copy this down here and let's look only
at the large triangle the base of the
triangle is the two pieces added
together so it's going to be 9x plus 6.
and the height is going to be 2x plus 6
and this hypotenuse will still be 13x
this is a right triangle which means we
can use Pythagorean theorem the quantity
9x plus 6 squared plus the quantity 2x
plus 6 squared is equal to the quantity
13x squared so the right hand side's
pretty easy both the 13 and the X get a
squared and 13 squared is equal to 169.
nice and then on the left hand side
we're going to add these two things so
this squared means this thing multiplied
by itself and this squared means this
thing multiplied by itself so this 9x
plus 6 times 9x plus 6 you can multiply
it out or foil it it ends up giving us
81x squared plus 108x plus 36. and you
can do the same thing with this down
here here gives us 4x squared plus 24x
plus 36. 81x squared plus 4 is 85x
squared 108x plus 24x is 132x and 36
plus 36 is 72. let's subtract 169x
squared from both sides and this minus
this is negative 84x squared we can
bring the rest of this stuff down and
this is all going to be equal to zero
each of these coefficients is divisible
by 12 so let's divide it by 12. now
let's do negative 12 so we can make the
leading coefficient positive negative 84
divided by negative 12 is 7x squared
positive 132 divided by negative 12 is
negative 11x positive 72 divided by
negative 12 is negative 6. and 0 divided
by negative 12 is 0. this is a quadratic
so let's use the quadratic formula both
of these A's are equal to seven both of
these B's are equal to negative 11 and
the C is equal to negative 6. after we
simplify all this we end up getting x
equals 2 or x equals negative 3 7. and
looking up here 13 times a negative
number would give us a negative
hypotenuse and we can't have a negative
hypotenuse so this x negative 3 7 is not
a valid solution to our problem that
leaves us with x equals two and that
looks important so let's put a box
around it so going back to our original
figure let's copy down the smaller
triangle now for both our larger
triangle and the smaller triangle let's
plug in 2 for all the X's 9 times 2 is
18 2 times 2 is 4 9 times 2 is 18 plus 6
is 24. 2 times 2 is 4 plus 6 is 10 and
13 times 2 is 26. now we have specific
values for our triangles I think we're
ready to find the area of the red region
the area of the red region will be equal
to this big triangle minus the small
triangle so let's figure out the area of
each of those the area of either of
these triangles is going to be base
times height divided by 2. for this big
triangle the base is equal to 24 and the
height is equal to 10 and we're still
going to divide by two and for the
smaller triangle the base is 18 the
height is 4 and then we're going to
divide by two and now let's simplify
these fractions 21 4 times 10 is 240 and
18 times 4 is 72. 240 divided by 2 is
120 and 72 divided by 2 is 36. so our
big triangle is 120 so let's change this
to 120 and our small triangle is 36
let's change this to 36. and 120 minus
36 is 84. so the area of our red region
is 84 units squared even though some of
the measurements were in terms of X we
were still able to get an exact value
for the area how exciting